What's it mean to be an American? There
has been a lot of talk about that in
this 250th anniversary year. And for the
New York based ensemble called the
Public Quartet, the answer has a lot to
do with rhythm. In fact, Rhythm Nation
is the title of the band's new album.
And yes, they borrowed the title from
Janet Jackson. They were inspired by her
1989 album as a beacon of inclusion. And
there's a lot of inclusion going on in
this album, including rhythms from many
places like West Africa and music of
Foday Musa Suso. J Balta
>> [music]
[music]
>> The Public Quartet believes in the
American melting pot theory where people
from all over come to this nation, bring
their rhythms, and of course their
culture, and we're all better off,
right? Like Eddie Venegas, Venezuelan
violinist and composer who wrote this
groove-laden track especially for the
Public Quartet.
>> [music]
>> On this album filled with rhythms of
many flavors, the Public Quartet is
helping redefine what a string quartet
means in the 21st century.